<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AFL on Hugo Apéro</title>
    <link>/tags/afl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AFL on Hugo Apéro</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/afl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Discovery and Characterisation of Forward-Line Formations at Centre Bounces in the Australian Football League</title>
      <link>/project/2022-08-26-formations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/2022-08-26-formations/</guid>
      <description>Project is the final year thesis for the Master of Sport Analytics at La Trobe University. It is currently unavailable due to sensitive information. Feel free to contact me regarding any questions. See below for some example plots. Figure 1: Metrics captured in one stage of the analysis.
Figure 2: Latter method of assessing differences between centre bounces.
Figure 3: Proportional use of positions by anonymised teams in their forward lines at centre bounces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY Dangerousity in the AFL</title>
      <link>/project/2021-10-02-diy-dangerousity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/2021-10-02-diy-dangerousity/</guid>
      <description>Task 1 - Dangerousity Equation Link et al. [1] introduced the idea of dangerousity in their paper entitled Real-Time Quantification of Dangerousity in Soccer Using Spatiotemporal Tracking Data. Dangerousity can be referred to as the “quantitative representation of the likelihood of a goal”. This concept attempts to explain the scoring opportunity at any time a player possesses the ball (the paper explores dangerousity through soccer). Various contextual measures formulated together create this metric.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
